right like you don't want to be taking
somebody who has that kind of talent and
is struggling and then abusing that like
their time and their energy and stuff
and not giving them money even if it's a
small amount of money that's going to
change their life right like give them
the $150 or whatever that that you were
going to spend on team lunch or whatever
the [__] and like you know like change
somebody's life instead of having a VDP
that's my call the action
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone we've all heard of project
Discovery right the authors of nuclei
htpx and countless other essential
security tools what you may not have
heard of however is their conference
hardly strictly security conference this
conference is happening April 25th from
8:00 a.m. onward virtual
and it's featuring the topic of
everything open source security tooling
they'll have speakers from top companies
like versel data dog hash Corp and
fastly and it's oriented towards anybody
who cares about open source security
tooling whether you're a Bug Hunter a
red teamer security leader whoever uh
there should be great content for you at
this conference so if you're interested
head over to
nu.
hs24 hss2 24 right uh hardly strictly
security and then 2024 uh to sign up and
register and get in on that conference
goodness all right with that back to the
show now let's just go ahead and start
it and okay you were saying you said
when you're using kaido we're just gonna
get this on air when you're using kaido
what's going on yeah so I still I'm
still going back and forth between kaido
and burp um I've gotten into some like
more complex workflows recently like
more technical type of um like binary
content and like weird protocols and
stuff and I found that it's just these
things don't work as well in kaido like
kaido works really well for just sort of
like standard type of HTTP work right
like plain text for plain text requests
plain text responses um and when you
start to dive into more the binary
aspects and stuff for example there's no
hex editor right like that's a that's a
great example right so like I was
working with I want to say like protuff
or something selecting btes in protuff
and like relying on like the system
clipboards would be copying those like
Vice correctly and all it's just like I
don't trust it and I don't know how to
verify it and all that kind of stuff so
I just end up going to birth for those
types of things yeah um I had the same I
had the same thing the other day with
that like like I was and that's one of
the topics for today was I was taking a
look at some of the code behind air chat
and they use grpc on the back end for
their API and uh it's binary based so I
was like uh and like there are so many
characters that I couldn't even see and
I was like I don't even know how this is
working this is kind of magic and then I
put it into burp and saw like turn on
Hex mode and I saw a bunch of bites that
I was kind of messing up which is why I
was getting bad responses so um yeah the
hex editor it's a big thing for those
those you know protuff or grpc based
targets yeah for sure and like it's not
I I'm sure you can make kaido do it with
workflows and custom commands and all
that kind of stuff but that when I'm
using a proxy that's not the type of
stuff I want to be fighting with at this
time it need to be it needs it needs to
like work well with my flow because if
I'm spending a lot of time trying to
make kaido work like burp then that's
taking away from the time that I can
spend hacking and it's just like not an
efficient use of my time and I will
rabbit hole into that it's been like
four hours making kaido do this one
thing the same as burp and then I'll be
like wait what was I doing again and
it's you know I just find that I have to
kind of um you know if I get into those
situations just you know call call it
and say okay kaido's not there yet
switch to bur and then maybe I'll switch
back or you know it kind of just depends
on the workflow or the target yeah I
think it's a maturity thing too you know
burp has been around for so long they're
and they have a really developed plug-in
system where you can in you know import
like blackbox um Proto buff and all
sorts of plugins for these various
systems that people have Rabbid hold on
and built just like you were talking
about for burp um so I I think as kaido
continues to mature um you know we'll
we'll see that stuff as well and and we
are seeing it already you know there's
new plugins getting released for kaido
all the time um shout out to mon for uh
was it kaido pets and kaido nerd stpe
did you see kaido nerd stpe I didn't see
kaido nerd type but I oh actually yes I
did yes I did okay yeah yeah yeah so
essentially he this is based off of the
conversations we've had in uh in you
know the on the Pod but essentially you
know it adds a right click Send to Joel
you know right click Send to Justin
interface on kaido which I think is like
super clutch and um that's something
that I've kind of been lobbying for as
well for for those of you listening I'm
a I'm an adviser on kaido's board um and
one of the things I've been kind of
lobbying for uh within the kaido
ecosystem are sort of collaboration
based features I think that would be
really huge um so I I'm glad to see some
some pseudo collaboration features there
coming in from the plug-in context and
uh yeah let us know if you for those of
you listening let us know if uh if you'd
be interested in something like that
because uh might be able to push that
along through the system if we have any
um you know big promoters of that so
yeah absolutely yeah uh should we talk
about this this nagly thread by the way
while we're this is gonna open up a can
of worms yeah let's do it let's do it
okay so um I don't even remember if I
saw this like on my feet or if somebody
sent it to me or whatever but um Nagle
posted this big long thread this morning
right right at 6:00 a.m. uh totally not
scheduled um yeah but it was basically
just a rundown of you know sort of his a
brain dump from his thoughts and
opinions about bdps um vulnerability
disclosure programs right not bug Bounty
programs but the the non-paying programs
um and sort of you know why he feels
like you know they're they're really
negative for the platforms why they're
negative for hunters uh you know what
sort of load they create and whether or
not it's even worth having these sort of
things so real quick let's just sort
of go over the general claims right um
so first of all vdps are worse for bug
buny Hunters worse for paid bug buny
programs they're free labor um you can't
you know you can only find bugs on bdps
but you can't pivot that into bug buny
programs um the leaderboard stats get
skewed from bdps and um there are these
same scope programs where somebody has a
VDP that's like fully non-paying and
then they have a private bug Bounty
program with the same scope or a limited
subset of that scope that pays um but
they don't pay for everything so not a
big fan of that last one man that that
last one kind of gets my goat a little
bit not gonna lie yeah so I like
personally I rarely ever interact with
vdps but I will say my general stance on
vdps is fairly similar to nagle's I
don't think that vdps are really a good
use of resources for a lot of companies
especially the ones that are primarily
us using them um and generally speaking
I don't know about so much about like
you know the effects on other programs
and on hackers and all that kind of
stuff we can we we'll we can dive into
that for sure um but I definitely think
that a lot of the companies that are
using vdps shouldn't be using bdps and
what I mean by that is I mean let's call
it spus bit I think the greatest example
of this in history is the Red Bull
program okay or maybe or or maybe the
the Department of Defense I don't know
like there there's a lot of good defense
great example Ford you know another one
you know like I mean there's to many
examp yeah there's so many big companies
like that yeah almost too many good
examples to even be like here's the best
example right which is kind of goes and
talks about the problem doesn't it you
have these huge huge huge huge
multi-billion dollar companies okay real
quick we didn't plan this um Ford market
cap Ford's market cap is 49.1 15 billion
doll go red bull market
cap Red Bull's market
cap is unknown because I think they're
private but somewhere around
like10 billion do at least is that am I
reading that right and look at this dude
Ford's annual gross profit for 2023 was
25 billion so they're operating at like
50% profit margins so there's plenty of
space there for paying researchers 10
grand to find a crit yeah and I I will
say right it's not always about the
money like I think anybody who has
worked at a company has dealt with
finance and has seen sort of the reality
of you know just because a company makes
Revenue doesn't mean that that revenue
is accessible or usable by by
whatever that shouldn't stop you from
like emphasizing your security program
right like if you are a $50 billion
company you should have at least a
little bit of money where your mouth is
on your security team right it's an
investment too like I feel like most of
these these companies as well you know
it's nice to be able to say if you do
get popped for example right it's nice
to be able to say well we've been
running this bug boundy program and
we've been doing you know this and that
and the other thing and you know to at
least show like that you're working hard
you know to to to take your security
seriously and I just feel like VDP
doesn't do that yeah now that being said
I think there are
there are certainly companies and
candidates that fit into a category
where vdps make sense right you've got
smaller companies companies that don't
have this kind of funding maybe open-
Source projects um like the internet bug
Bounty stuff like and even them they
offer bounties right like you know I I
think that um there are certainly cases
that can be made for you know nonprofits
or whatever that who can fit into this
category of we want to be receiving
vulnerabilities we don't have the kind
of budget and money to pay huge amounts
but we want to recognize in another way
are vdps the solution for that I don't
know like again I I think vdps are like
a really crude way of like solving this
problem
where you want to recognize hackers for
their work but you don't want to do it
with money directly
and or necessarily incentivize hacking
on your program right or incentivize it
at all right because it's like points
it's it's magic internet points that are
up to the platform not even up to like
you as the company like there's no skin
in the game whatsoever for Ford to give
out 50 reputation points right it's
literally a click of a button no money
no nothing no anything um and that's not
a huge incentive for the program to do
things right that's not a huge incentive
for the researchers to even submit stuff
right if you find a vulnerability a
really critical vulnerability on a
program that has a uh a VDP where's your
incentive to report it directly to that
company so that you can get a pat on the
back and maybe a t-shirt or something
right like I I think that it's a really
um again it's a crude way of sort of
solving this problem and if we're going
to allow it to exist within the space of
bug bounty we should probably be
limiting limiting it to certain factors
right like what's your total revenue uh
are you a nonprofit like do you have um
any sort of like extra cash flow like
how many employees do you have like I
don't know I'm sure the platforms would
probably be better at creating those
sort of parameters but I think that vdps
are really really starting to take up a
space where they shouldn't be and every
single hacker I talked to who has
interacted with the VDP that should be
paying has the same exact reaction it's
like why isn't this company paying they
have the money to pay it right Red Bull
the dod I mean the dod is a little bit
of an edge case I think but um you know
I hate to pick on these two companies
because I know that there are other ones
that are I'm just like not thinking of
at the moment but I will say IBM sure
right like there are so many large
companies that make a ton of money and
could afford to pay and choose not to
yeah right yeah I I think I think one of
the top points that he made in this this
um tweet that he did was the fact that
bug crowd has dropped incentivization
for vdps and hacker one I remember them
sort of speaking out like yeah yeah that
makes sense you know we'll move in that
direction but they haven't and um and
and I I think that's one of the things
we're seeing with hacker one a little
bit too is this sort of like
compan isation of hacker one where it's
like okay how is this you know and not
to say that bug Crow integrity and all
the other ones aren't thinking about
their like margins or whatever but like
I imagine vdps and having active vdps is
a really good
onboarding place for hacker one right
like hey you know uh we've already got a
VDP set up like we get to talk to you
every you know couple months or whatever
to check in on the VDP or like give you
new findings and stuff it's enough touch
points where it's like okay sales
becomes much easier when you've got a
VDP I guarantee you there's some
dashboard some Metric inside of you know
hacker one sales presentations where
it's like you know 28% of vdps convert
to actual bug Bounty you know customers
or something like that um after a
certain period of time so um I I don't
necessarily blame them for for I do I do
blame them I I really think it should
not be incentivized and I also hate the
fact that there are private vdps um
that's something that for those of you
that that that don't know you can that
off in your settings um on hacker one
and your invite preferences pretty much
all the top hackers and all of the
mentees of the top hackers have this
turned off like it's one of the first
things you do when you set up your
hacker One account um so I would
definitely recommend turning those off
and I don't yeah hacker one needs to get
rid of those because it's just bad for
the ecosystem yeah and somebody actually
mentioned in a reply here apparently and
I I I haven't verified this but yes we
hack has no vdps at all right so um you
know some of the platforms have taken a
really really Hardline approach with
this where they're not having any vdps
whatsoever I think the bottom line is
that not only from a program perspective
but or sorry not only from a platform
perspective but from a program
perspective you should be paying for
security vulnerabilities even if it's a
little bit of money right that's almost
a separate discussion of if your Bounty
table is too low and if you should be
raising it but the fact that there are
these companies that are not paying at
all really says a lot about sort of how
they view external security research and
how they handle that internally right
like if you had a really serious
vulnerability the the there's no proper
formal route to get a hold of their
security team maybe you could email them
or you know you could I guess you could
submit it through their VDP but you know
it really just says a lot about sort of
where the priorities are for these for
these companies especially the really
really big ones that aren't paying um so
I would love to see a more Hardline
stance on this the for the platforms
what what is your thought on his like
metric of like okay there should be
roughly and these are rough calculations
and I I tagged ybert to see if we get
actual numbers on this but if there's a
similar number of submissions
to vdps as there are bug Bounty programs
you you're spending you know your triage
is spending half of your time triaging
VDP bugs um and that is a lot that is a
lot of overhead so I mean what what do
you think about that yeah so I will say
um I don't know how that works I assume
that hacker 1 has separate triage teams
for paying customers that they do than
they do for VDP customers um so it's
hard for me to make a claim about
whether or not that extra you know
triage load and the triage burnout and
the excess report load and all that kind
of stuff it's really hard to say whether
or not that's valid that being said if
tomorrow there was a a switch that was
flipped and these VDP programs were now
private programs Not only would they pay
the same amount for Tre out services but
well actually I don't know I mean they
must pay for tri Services
if right so they're probably going to
say that pay the same amount for tri
Services maybe a little bit more because
it's dedicated question mark I'm not
sure um
but really it's the same triage load
right like you still have the same
number of triage people who are going to
be dealing with the same number of
reports and all that kind of stuff it's
really just maybe more reports and you
know more money overall so it's a
private program though now so the their
volume isn't going to be quite as much
though well they could be a public
paying program right they could be yeah
they could but going from a VDP to a
public paying program is a pretty ballsy
move I think that the best practice is
like go you know from VDP to Buck Bounty
private Buck Bounty you know run that
for a year two clean up your attack
surface and then jump right into public
program so this gets to one of the other
problem points doesn't it because the
cat is now out of the bag and so you've
created an issue where you have a public
VDP but you want to start paying for
things but you don't want to go zero to
100 so what do you do you create a
private paying bug Ry program with the
same
scope and you start to pay researchers
for those vulnerabilities who are
invited and you run that for a couple
years and event
you either phase it over to public or
what they probably do is they see oh wow
we're still getting a lot of reports on
this public bdp and we're getting a lot
of reports on this private private bug
Bounty program why would we ever merge
the two because now we're going to pay a
lot more money right and they just never
do well yeah and and here's here's the
thing I I spoke with somebody who runs a
public VDP and a private program public
program I said why are you doing that
and and they said something that was
kind of interesting um they said that
they actually pay the VDP submissions um
if they meet a certain threshold of
reporter so the lows and the lower
mediums they will let sit in the VDP and
just accept the report through the VDP
the mediums and above um the it's a the
mediums the upper mediums are sort of a
judgment call do we bring them into the
private program pay them for it or do we
just accept it and invite them to the to
the private program and then highs and
crits all get moved to the the bug
Bounty program and paid and so I was
like okay you know that's kind of
interesting so it's sort of like an
onboarding mechanism for the people that
are using your app notice a bug and and
submit it and then you're not robbing
them okay so so let me pick your brain
about that a little bit so first of all
is do all the submissions go through the
VDP or are some people on both and they
just you everybody everybody who's in
the private program just submits to the
private
program okay and so anything that's you
know medium high end of medium or above
and should be in the main program gets
moved from and came in through VDP gets
moved to the main program and then
exactly and then they they pay it off
they pay it you know they pay the
researcher for that submission even
though they submitted to a VDP okay so
how do you feel think it's kind of a
good idea right like like to be honest
I'd be pretty happy if for some reason
you know I submitted a bug to a VDP in
some World Justin submitted a bug to a
VDP um then and I got it got moved into
the buck Bing program and I got paid for
it I would have a ton of you know sort
of brand affinity for that for that
Target right okay so so how as a hacker
how do you feel about that process of
not only having sort of two places to
report um
but getting paid like regardless of the
VDP existence like if you submit a good
bug you're still going to get paid like
does does that still annoy you in the
same way that they have a VDP you know
so I said in the beginning I really
don't like that structure and I think
what I don't like about it is the fact
that if you had known somebody who's in
the public program or the private
program then and you sent them a DM
saying hey I got a bug can you submit it
you know and they submit it to the
program then it's like okay so why can't
I just submit it to the program or like
you know you you DM someone and say Hey
you know I know this this program's got
like a private program can can I get
added to it or whatever I found a bug
there um and you can't really submit a
bug to the VDP and be like hey I've got
a bug but I know you've got a bug Bounty
program so give me access to that
because that just feels extortion right
so it's like I don't know it it the the
times when they don't pay the researcher
is is not great but the times when they
do pay the researcher anyway I'm
actually not super opposed to that
structure I don't know maybe that's off
so here's a followup let's say they had
a public paying bug Bounty program they
merged the two but they had the same
policy lows and lows and anything under
5.5 or whatever CVSs zero Bounty they
only pay they'll accept everything but
they'll only give bounties for things
that are medium and
above yeah I mean I don't love it to be
honest with you okay you know it's the
same thing but I don't love it you know
okay feels bad why because they might as
well just pay for it all if they're
going to pay for some of it or it's just
not competitive at that point like it's
like why would I spend time on this
right because there's there's plenty of
programs that pay for lows and mediums
and you know you know I'm a big medium
Advocate I I love a good medium man I
love a good medium um okay what if the
incentive is like high enough like let's
say like you know lows and mediums but
hypothetically flat payout for lows and
mediums let's say it's like 500 bucks
and then like high ends of mediums and
highs started like
5K you know if if they're paying 500 for
medium and this is a newer program you
know you know it's not it's not the
worst my standard is 750 for a medium uh
it's moving towards 1K for a medium
actually um but yeah I don't know man I
feel like I feel
like when you when you pulled that you
know hit me with that Uno reverse UNO
card there and I was like oh wait a
second I would hate that if it was if it
was a public Bounty program with no lows
and medium bounties it kind of opens the
eyes I just think the VDP is like I
think it makes sense that structure
makes sense for people that don't want
to get overwhelmed but also want to pay
researchers what they do and so that's
kind of why I like like that approach um
does that make sense yeah yeah I think
it's fair enough I was just kind of
curious from like you know the full-time
hackers perspective of like what you
know because it's basically same thing
right it's basically the same thing
because you know basically there's still
not paying for lows and whatevers but
they're just being transparent that if
something higher comes in they're going
to pay for it but um I don't know man
there's there's a different thing
because you know the full-time bug
Bounty Hunter this is a different this
is a different conversation because most
most companies don't want or aren't
going to be on our radar right the the
only people that are going to be on our
radar are people that are really top
level programs right because we're going
to be working with them long term we're
going to have a committed relationship
with that program um
and if you're not ready to pay up for
that like I've been talking to some
programs recently I've said hey look I
love your program I use your product all
the time you know normally just as a
part of my life I would love to hack you
because I know this product inside
outside upside down and I've got all my
data in it and I've got everything
configured right be awesome your
bounties aren't there you know I can't
do it because of this this this you know
and and it's just it's a shame but it's
also where some program are at maturity
wise is they they can only pay to
incentivize mid-grade hackers and that's
fine okay now here's this this is going
to get a little
deep spending longer than I anticipated
on this target I'm let you I'm let you
cook because this you're a program
manager so this is like yeah no I think
this is a good conversation so so I will
say like there's definitely a weird
balance coming I've noticed and I don't
think many people have noticed it but I
certainly have noticed it between
like Revenue
budgets
inflation and Bounty tables okay and you
could probably already sort of piece the
those things together but for one the
economy is like doing all sorts of weird
weird things right weird weird things
right now inflation is still through the
roof and continuing to go up at like a
really crazy rate I haven't checked that
recently that's interesting Bounty
tables are also inflating in my opinion
quite significantly not fast enough from
the hacker perspective but way too fast
from a program perspective what and Joel
don't open up this can of worms right
now are you kidding me well I mean just
think about this okay think about this
criticals a good critical on on a on a
bug Bounty program in
2019 would be 10K like that's like the
high end of of crits like at most of
program is paying 20K crits okay like
top top programs
2019 2024 there
are plenty of companies who offer at
least 50k crits 100K crits even higher
especially for the crypto programs yeah
that that's okay A a solid crit payment
right now is 20K like I will look at a
program that has a 20K crit if you want
to get above a 20 crk crit that's when
you you get really into the like okay
this is on The Hit List like I will hack
this program at some point you know true
but the 50k ones I almost and and I've
gotten a couple 50k bounties and it's
great and it feels awesome but they are
hard to get the companies to pay and
they are oftentimes on very specialized
scope yeah right so I will say like I I
think the hard part is not so much that
like most people are ending up paying
those critical bounties I think it's
more that because the T
ends up there the next levels have to be
significantly higher right so high
vulnerabilities starting at like 10 or
15K and medium starting at like five or
two and a half right those are yeah you
love to see it but then from like a
program perspective you make one little
slip up there's one like medium severity
vulnerability and it's like thousands of
dollars out of the budget right and so
um in order to be competitive like you
said like a top level hacker you see a
program that's paying
like 3K 5K I don't know is 5K crits
enough for you to hack or not anymore so
five 5K crits I will not I will not
normally hack on um unless I am have
some other Inc incentivization right so
that's like still pretty good like
that's probably the average crit payout
for most programs that don't have a ton
of budget and you know there are
basically off radar for a lot of the top
hackers because they can't compete
financially with the Bounty tables that
the really big programs have and so they
just can't attract that attention and so
it's just a very very difficult
situation I think like I'd love to see
Bounty tables continue to grow and and
companies are continuing to put more and
more money behind you know their their
security teams and all that kind of
stuff but then either those single slip
UPS or in order to stay competitive and
have an edge against other programs it's
like there's always that like classic
joke right of like the lemonade stand
right where you're like there's two guys
selling lemonade and one guy's at like
40 cents and the other guy's at 50 cents
and so then the guy next to him drops
his down to 40 cents and then the guy
next to him drops his to 30 cents and
then 20 cents 10 cents and then the guy
next to him buys all of his product puts
him out of business and raises it back
to 40 cents right and so it's just like
the kind of the same thing but without
like the acquisition cost so much where
basically there's a race to the top for
Bounty tables where the programs who
have highest bounties and the least
vulnerabilities get the most attention
or like close to the top and a lot of
scope you know what I mean like there's
a balance between scope and and bounties
where you're on yeah epic games
uh let's let's we gotta be careful you
know what I'm saying I know what you're
saying I know what you're saying yeah
yeah um yeah other examples Shopify um
you know but yeah there are definitely
it's it's kind of like a race to the top
with the Bounty tables where the higher
the Bounty table the more attention and
and sort of stuff you get um but then it
becomes even harder for smaller programs
to compete with that at all because
there's so much attention being garnered
from these 15K highs 5K mediums right
and so it's like that's part of the game
like like it is part of the game but you
know we're also simultaneously saying oh
you know like [__] vdps like you should
be a paying program and then they become
a paying program and they were like
screw you we don't it doesn't even
matter because they can't even compete
right like they can't even like they
can't put 20K crits down so like yeah
it's definitely a challenging at least
you're G to get at least you're going to
get the the the mid tier hackers though
and and there are some very very very
talented mid-tier hackers you know yeah
and and you know this whole hacker tier
system that I'm talking about is like
totally arbitrary and like yeah
essentially a figment of our imagination
you know there are some every every
hacker has their unique eyes and are
going to be able to find something that
other hackers can't find we see that
every single live hacking event um but
yeah I mean you're still going to
attract some hackers that have lower
standards dude if you live if I lived in
Argentina you know if I lived in in
India you know if I lived in some of
these places where like the amount of
money you need to spend to have an
awesome life is so much less than I
would absolutely hack on a 5k crit
program because it's like okay that 5K
crit results in You Know This Much spend
for me which is the lifestyle that I
want to live and there are tons I know
many many many hackers that are very
skilled doing the digital Nomad thing
where if they get 5K they're set for you
know two months and it's like I will say
I think like that's probably one of the
like
hugest like lifechanging aspects of bug
Bounty like it's always been like you
know life-changing amounts of money to
some extent depending on where you are
but I think especially in countries that
are a lot more like their economies are
struggling a lot more they're um a lot
less developed and stuff
like what we would call a small Bounty
right like $500 or something I mean walk
up to anybody and give them $500 outside
the US and even in in the US right it's
like it's a it's a huge amount of money
right and so I think um bugman is like
doing a ton in that area but there's
still too many bdps right like you don't
want to be taking somebody who has that
kind of talent and is struggling and
then abusing that like their time and
their energy and stuff and not giving
them money even if it's a small amount
of money that's going to change their
life right like give them the $150 or
whatever that that you were G to spend
on team lunch or whatever the [__] and
like you know like change somebody's
life instead of having a VDP yeah that's
my call to action yeah I I agree man no
it's good it's good and it's it's funny
you know I I talked to somebody that got
actually a massive Bounty and lives in
one of these countries that it's like
this is literally like hitting the
lottery you know it's like you know your
life has changed forever your family's
life has changed forever it's like it's
it's crazy so um really exciting for
people living in those in those regions
of the world and uh yeah for anybody who
is willing to make that lifestyle switch
to go and live in those countries
because um you know lots of lots of a
awesome opportunities there um sorry I
didn't I didn't mean to derail that too
much uh you're good man I'm looking at
your program here man you got you got
the Tinder program 10 10K highs you know
uh 2K mediums at at
minimum all right all right I'm just
saying what do I need to do to compete
I'm sorry man I see the thing is I don't
use Tinder like if I was a single dude
if I was a single dude that uses Tinder
which there's two two big two big
conditions that are not fulfilled here
um then I would I would absolutely hack
on it um but uh you know I don't so that
that's saying is I think we both known
that um sometimes those barriers make
for great programs to hack on because it
it it deters a lot of people so even if
you are uh a non- single person who
doesn't use Tinder if you're willing to
get on Tinder and use Tinder and and try
and hack it um you know you'll have an
edge on other people make sure you tell
your wife in advance yeah honey I yeah g
to get some weird DMS from your single
friends like um Justin yeah yeah oh
that's great okay so I we actually have
another kind of like program hacker
debate uh okay hold up hold up hold up
actually I'm sorry I'm not done with
this nogly tweet ngly you screwed us
here man because now we're talking 30
minutes into this podcast still on the
same thing um what do you think about
the leaderboard thing like I I thought
that was I think that is one of the
things that needs to change absolutely
is like you know this whole gamification
piece of bug Bounty is awesome and is a
major major major motivator for a lot of
the hackers um and hackers that spend
times on hard like the hackers like
myself and others that spend time
specifically looking for the Harden the
most hardened programs they can find you
know um and and try to try to hack on
these programs are not seeing as good of
a return or as good of placement on
these leaderboards or even people that
just hack bug Bounty programs in general
uh because of the presence of VP and
somebody commented I I want to say it
was let me look down here I want to say
it was piku Haku um from the Discord
yeah um and said that essentially uh the
number one hacker on Integrity right now
too is a VDP only program and I saw them
kind of get into it on Twitter the other
day there's like a Twitter argument
about like you know you found 28 bugs or
whatever and I found 28 bugs this
morning you know and it's like who's the
better hacker and I'm like uh the guy
that's hacking
the the paid program for sure um so I I
don't know what are your thoughts on
that yeah so I I I also
like gamification is fine right I I I I
think everything's going to get gamified
if they don't do it some other hacker is
going to do it right nagle's
intelligence Network or whatever he's
going to build his own leaderboard and
whatever but that being said these are
not the same thing right bdps and and by
branding programs I don't think are the
same thing and the fact that there is um
this alternative method of earning the
same points like it doesn't feel right
to me if we're gonna have points let's
keep it what it is right and let's
either delineate it separately bug
Bounty reputation VDP reputation VDP
signal VDP you know whatever
or don't even include it entirely do
what bugb crowd did remove the points
aspect from it you don't get any points
for any of that stuff it doesn't affect
your stats at all if you want to be a
good guy hacker and you want to submit
stuff to vdps and you want to get your
practice on there that's great but
you're not going to get any stats for
that because yeah that's not bug bunny
program reflective stats that's bdp
reflective stats yeah and you know I'm
not I think it should be a separate
leaderboard I think you know I think you
should get bug Bounty rep and you should
get other rep because it is a good
resume why hide it right like yeah if
you want if you spend a bunch of time
doing that that's fine but I think to
make to combine them is a little bit
misleading both to people who look at
the leaderboards but also to the people
who are like trying to get up on the
leaderboard right you could go hack on a
bunch of VDP programs that are have much
more scope lower barrier for entry like
easier to farm points all that kind of
stuff and you see exactly what's
happening the people on the top of the
leaderboards um or a lot of the people
who are in the top of of the
leaderboards are VDP hackers right they
there people who are hacking on vdps
they're earning a ton of points from
from vdps and to try and compete from a
purely bug Bounty program perspective
extremely extremely difficult like you
would have to go out of your way to
probably hack on vdps just to get points
so that you can compete on the same
number of reports and all that kind of
stuff if you're just a bug binding
program hacker and again it's fine like
to hack on vdps get the points for it
that's great but from the programs or
sorry I keep missing mixing from the
platform hack bug right they should be
listing these things separately don't
put somebody's you know 10,000 rep when
8,000 of that is from the dod program
and 2,000 of it is from pay programs
right like put that separate so that
people can see oh they've got a ton of
rep from this I I think this actually
extends um even further uh if we're if
we're going to talk about leaderboards
this is a complaint I've had about this
as well is like the program leaderboards
do the same exact problem right you go
to any program you look at their leader
you see who's on the top of the
leaderboard right top five top 10 going
to have thousands and thousands of rep
but you go and look look at uh the
thanked hackers and you look at this
year you could go back I I've I've done
this like five years back six years back
until I actually hit when they got 2,000
rep on that program when the top hacker
and that hacker hasn't hacked on this
program since before covid and they're
still at the top of the leaderboard
because they farmed the hell out of the
program when it first launched they got
a ton of rep and they haven't touched it
since and you're looking at this and
you're like wow how am I ever going to
get 4,000 rep on this program and it's
it's just very hard to get like an
accurate right it's a different game
it's a different perspective and like
yeah alltime stats that person really
crush the program but so much has
changed since then they might have a
different scope they might have
different bounties they might have a
different everything and you're still
seeing this person as the number one
hacker on this program um and I and I
think like it's it's a similar aspect
where it's really hard like you can
infer a lot of things and I think a lot
of people are inferring the wrong things
when they see these right you look at
the top leaderboard you see somebody
with 10,000 rep you're thinking this
person hacks a lot they make a lot of
bounties they're getting a lot of really
valid reports if you were to see the
breakdown of bbp versus VDP rep it's
probably going to tell a very different
picture and the same thing goes for you
know like the the rep on the top hackers
on a program let's look at how much rep
they've gotten in the last 90 days or
the last three or last 360 days 365 days
instead of all time and it's going to
tell a very different picture yeah I I
think this is a great point for hacker
one too is like that top hacker they
moved that to the Bottom by the way I
don't know if you noticed that but I
don't I don't love that uh but they they
moved it to the bottom and it defaults
to top hackers of all time I think it
should default to the last 365 days
because and I think hack one would
really benefit from that too because
common mistake in the beginning everyone
made it like you mentioned was going
there and being like Oh you know
freaking today's new has like you
know a thousand rep on this program I'm
never going to find anything yeah you
know one flood mentality we've talked
about this many times we're not going to
repeat it again but two he hasn't
touched the program in you know a year
or two years and so if you do that
running leaderboard one that's
incentivizes you to continue to hack on
a program if you want to maintain your
leaderboard status but also it doesn't
scare away those people that are um just
not gonna you look at the program if
some top hacker has been looking at it
in in the past you know year or whatever
so I I think it could be a really good
move for hacker one and I think it would
help um sort of solidify some of that uh
that yeah yeah and what I'll say is just
as a as a recent example of this with
the public program Shopify okay you go
to shopify's alltime leaderboard their
top hacker h13 Dash he's got 3,900 rep
all time you set that to 2024 he's not
even on he's not even listed you set
that to 2023 not even listed you said
that to 2022 now he's listed he's got
680 rep right so we're two years
out well a year and a half whatever and
that this hacker hasn't even they're
still at the top of the leaderboards
right so this it's just not a very
accurate way of sort of looking at
things and I think it's a little too
broad and and generalized in terms of
like how a lot of stats are being shown
um and how the leaderboards and stuff
work um and yeah I think it would be
good to see a little bit more separation
and granularity on that data from just
like a user's perspective of if I just
visit someone's program or someone's
profile maybe only show the bug Bounty
program rep and stats by default and if
I want to see their bdp rep and stats
there's a drop down
or or something like that you know like
right right show both at the same time
or yeah whatever right like there's got
to be a better way to show this that's
not as confusing um and not as easy to
sort of game right because I I think a
lot of this boils down to people are
gaming this in a negative way that's not
fair to the people who aren't gaming it
yeah yeah I agree and and so yeah I
think that leaderboard piece could be
really cool I I got a little nerd sniped
for a second um you know because I I
looked at the activity on Shopify and I
see our boy M bear is just crushing it
out here this man is getting Bounty over
Bounty over
so nice job dude rocking it hey guys
real quick I just wanted to give a shout
to the hacker content team they have
been absolutely killing it the past
couple months taking the content from
the podcast and condensing it down into
consumable social media posts whether it
be shorts or text posts or whatever
they've been rocking it so uh I just
wanted to give them a shout out and let
you know that they do all sorts of
cybercity content as well as social
media management they do technical blogs
they do uh comprehensive social media
management uh so if your organization
could benefit from any of those those
types of services make sure you head
over to hacker content.com drop them a
line and mention the podcast when you do
to get your first month of cyber
security content marketing services for
free all right that's it let's get back
to the pot you know what I think we're
gonna cut nog's tweet off there ngi
thanks for 40 minutes of content this uh
this this week gez dude um okay so yeah
let's continue the whole uh program uh
versus hacker debate you know version
two somebody was asking about this in
the Discord too so um it's good we we
fell into that um let me ask you about
this so um I've run into this situation
a couple times in the past where there
is
a very common issue that happens across
many many end points on a Target
okay and this this issue is
um let's say
it's there an issue more often than
there's not an issue with this target
with these specific set of end points
with this specific vulnerability okay
okay but there are endpoints that have
the correct access controls in place
okay so clearly there's some access
control system in
place what do you think
about making it like up seeing you know
20 reports come in for the specific um
thing and realizing hey our current
implementation is flawed and really we
should just shove this off in middleware
or something like that um but then
you've got to undo all of the code in
those other functions and then put the
middleware in and then you know so it's
not it's it's sort of a global fix but
also you're undoing code in functions
that were not vulnerable whereas the
normal standard would be like okay if I
changed uh you know some code in this
specific function for this specific
endpoint then it's a fix for that
endpoint and that gets a unique Bounty
that's the normal standard um but so
rather than that you fix at the
middleware level and then you remove the
previous you know fla checks from the
end points that were not vulnerable
um I feel like that's sort of a sneaky
way to get around it and I feel like
what would happen is if you sent in one
report at a time then they'd be like oh
I just need to copy and paste this you
know Access Control check from this
function into that function then they
fix it in that individ individual
function then you send the next one then
you send the next one you know and so do
you continue with this sort of
incomplete or sort of flawed model um or
do you you know try to take a different
approach and if you learned from the the
hacker submitting 20 reports that this
is a you know massive problem do you pay
them for all 20 reports uh and then you
know I don't know what what are your
thoughts on that you see what I'm saying
I don't know if that was yeah yeah yeah
so I I'll talk generically about this um
so my stance is that generally these
things kind of end up working themselves
out almost the same way um and so
typically what happen let's let's run
through both scenarios the first
scenario is that um you have this semi-
systemic issue you find it on a lot of
different endpoints you're submitting
them one at a time as the program gets
them they pay them basically Pro let's
say the same Bounty for every single one
um and and that's sort of how it goes
the other way is that you submit uh or
maybe there's three options the the
second option is that you submit uh all
20 at the same time and
they or is that are those just the two
options for submissions either you slow
roll them or or you do them all once so
you
know the Slow Roll I think it it's
pretty clear that if they fix it
globally from the slow roll then then
it's not a global issue you know it's
not an issue that you should get paid
for each one of them
um then other hand there is that aspect
of like okay well we looked at the code
and we found 20 other functions that you
couldn't see because they're not in the
JS files and we don't have any API docs
leaking you know that we're as
vulnerable and this is actually a
massive issue um so I don't know second
yeah that second scenario like if if the
program discovers significantly more
impact fact that it was a systemic issue
they didn't know about I would say nine
times out of 10 nine and a half times
out of 10 9.9 times out of 10 program is
never going to even let you know that
that was a thing yeah um and they're
gonna fix I thought you were gon to say
the offic I was like do do not say that
like hell no hell no no no mo I mean
obviously it's in the programs like best
interest to pay as little money as
possible Right like that's that's where
the incentive lies um uh that's just you
know economics right what is wrong with
you man the Hacker's uh goal to earn as
much money as possible it's the
program's job to pay as little money as
possible right that's just how the
economics uh work um that being said
there is like ethics an Ethics side here
right so I think like a really highly
ethical and transparent program which
are very few of who go to this length
would be like hey as we were just
looking into this we found that this is
actually a really huge problem so we're
going to pay it out that is rare for a
lot of reasons mainly like money because
it's literally just like lighting extra
money on fire and like going to find an
impact where you're going to pay more
money um it you know it's it's rarely a
a
good
justification when you're like trying to
explain why you paid 50 instead of
paying like 20 you know what I mean um
yeah so so there's there's that aspect
to it um like that scenario however I
think as I was saying most of the time
these sort of
merge into the same sort of resolution
because if you submit 20 of the same
vulnerability then they for sure know
okay like there's some sort of weird
systemic thing here we need to look into
this and figure out what's going on and
they're going to fix it systemically and
most likely I would say the program's
gonna pay a higher Bounty but close
those all as one issue because it's
going to get fixed in one place um if
you were to slow roll them initially
they're going to fix them one at a time
and then after like four they're going
to be like this is probably systemic and
they're going to look into well they
should they should look into it find
that that it's systemic and then every
single report after that they're going
to say okay this is a known issue we're
working on fixing this we're not going
to pay them out as as additional
bounties um and then it's probably close
to the same Bounty depending on how many
reports you you managed to sneak through
or what they PID for it yeah right um
and maybe as a researcher you could make
that case and be like hey you know I
actually had a bunch more of these like
can we agree on you know paying like a
portion of you know like the total that
I had found or what you know I don't
know that that's a little more
complicated but I think generally the
program if they're doing their job well
like after four or five of the same type
of report on like you know systemic
thing they should be seeing okay this is
weird this looks like it's a semic let's
figure out what's going on here and
again we're back into the the incentive
model mod here where like the program is
going to try want to try and get on top
of it they're going to try and figure
out what's going on in the back end they
want to create tickets to make sure that
they're getting ahead of this so that
when more reports come in for that same
issue they can say oh we're actually
already working on a fix here dude can I
just go back to your whole like the
program is incentivized to not pay just
like dude okay so here here's what I
don't get I understand the whole ethical
conundrum of like okay I have been
entrusted with this responsibility um by
my employer and I should be giving my
employer you know my best effort and
that sort of thing um but also these are
massive massive companies that have you
know massive massive revenue and and
stuff and these researchers are doing
quality research that that are fixing
vulnerability this is not like we paid
500 grand for nessus you know it's
like this is this is actual here's a vul
a valid vul you fix here's the money you
know it's a pretty clear exchange and
it's high value as in you're getting
something worth money for what you're
paying um so I don't understand people's
hesitancy to push
around and and maybe this this is comes
from my my experience you know not
having to deal with Finance but you know
pushing around and saying like Hey
listen we have technical you know debt
we have problems that we need to fix
that were taken from improper
architecting and and cutting edges in
you know sometimes whatever it is in in
in code development and and that's a
price we need to pay and it's not
something that you can really say no to
because it's putting users at risk and
that risk is much greater than the you
know 2K we're going to get so I I just
like if I were on your side I feel like
I would say I I am fighting for the
researcher as much as to pay them as
much as I can because they're they're
they're producing value and I can see
that and I can validate that and I don't
have as much high hopes for other money
that's being spent in the organization
about whether you know Jim is spending
you know two two hours a week at the
freaking watering you know talking to
people and shooting the [__] and then
going to his company paid lunch for you
know two hours it's like like maybe I'm
being too too pessimistic on that but I
just I feel like there's so much BS in
so many companies especially when you
get above a certain size where people
are not actually doing anything for the
money they're they're they're getting
and Bug Bounty is always going to be a
here's something worth value yeah so bug
Bounty is like a weird it's like if it
falls into a weird spot right because
it's both it it assigns a financial
value to like security problems and it
it puts like a really hard dollar value
on like it
mistakes um and we try not to like
assign blame on things but it makes it
really difficult not to when you pay a
$10,000 Bounty and it's like okay you're
not paying that the company's paying
like well okay so think this how this
works you know where you get a think
about this way no no no it's not even
about the budget side right think about
it this way okay you paid $10,000
because uh security vulnerability was
found who should have found
that okay I see where this is going you
know maybe the security team or a code
review or something like that or the
person that wrot it yeah and when should
they have found it when they were
developing it yeah there's actually like
multiple places where they probably
should have found it right like during
review during like pre-review during
pre-release like during Post Release
like there's many many different spots
where like the security team probably
had opportunities to to identify that
vulnerability and didn't and now there's
is that what you're saying or the the
security team well right like yeah the
security team or the mostly like the
security team as a whole we'll just say
like somebody somebody somewhere within
the security team probably at some point
should have had an opportunity to
identify that if they didn't the process
is not great um and that like speaks to
other thing right but there's like this
sense of blame where it now there's like
a monetary value on this vulnerability
where somebody missed it and and now
that cost a lot of money and I
think that makes it a little bit easier
to justify to leadership in terms of
like hey there's a real cost of security
where if we don't find these
vulnerabilities and we don't have the
processes in place to be looking through
this stuff properly then it's going to
cost us a lot of money and
vulnerabilities but then there's also
the side
of I want to pay the
researcher at least as what's fair but
ideally as much as possible right and so
those two things are are like hard to
balance because paying what's fair can
be really tricky because maybe there's
like a legacy problem there's a lot of
vulnerabilities you didn't know about
now you you have like a budget problem
but paying as much as possible is also
like a a hard budget problem because now
you're like we want to pay as much money
we want to create as much spend on these
problems as possible to try and
incentivize them to be fix
but all it really does is make Finance
really annoyed that you're spending so
much money you know who cares who cares
about Annoying Finance like like I mean
maybe this is my this is very probably I
will preface this by saying this is from
a very privileged position of I have not
ever had to deal with corporate crap I I
did Consulting for two years and I've
been self-employed ever since and I
never going back um but also who cares
because at the end of the day it's not
like I feel like bug Bounty should have
that you know that that check of like
listen if you don't pay the money then
you're accepting the risk implicitly
that your users are going to get screwed
and that is so much more expensive like
look at the look at the um look at the
hack right total overall cost for that
like $110
million has run you know a bug Bounty
program for years and years and years
and they've only paid out what like 12
million you know like it's not it's like
the it's a drop right so I think cyber
like you know cyber security insurance
and stuff has also like all of the ways
of putting
monetary incentives and values on parts
of cyber security and like hacking and
stuff has created direct incentive
models where it's easier to justify to
the company why this spend needs to
exist and why it is what it is right and
I think that's that's very good um but
it's still like a hard like you still
have to sell it right because at the end
of the day it's always going to be a
financial burn where not only are you
like doing your security stuff but then
you're spending extra money to like pay
extra researchers and you know you you
have to somehow you know justify that
that money like for
finance I mean the reality is they'll
just give you less money you know what I
mean like it's a very privileged it's a
very privileg yeah sure sure they
control the budget right they say you
know we feel like you're spending too
much money so so you need to spend less
money and then the security team
basically has to figure out okay if
we're going to spend less money uh if we
want to pay the same amount in bounties
then we need to spend less money on
other things or we have to figure out
how to pay less bounties who does that
go up through because like what I what I
would how I would respond to that is
that you know Finance saying hey we're
going to pay you less money and then I
would try to get some statistics that
say okay you know this less money is
going to result in this amount of
decreased findings or this am of like oh
we don't have enough time to go over x
amount of code you know if you're even
talking about normal security stuff like
we need one more security engineer and
we're not going to get it so it's going
to be you know less amount of time
looking at this code which means x
amount of vulnerabilities introduced
which means X additional risk and then
you just push that up the line and you
say okay listen CEO like would you like
to in you know experience a TW you know
20% increase in uh cyber security risk
or would you like to pay an extra you
know 200 Grand or whatever it is a year
to get that down to a reasonable level
and then also have that in place with
you know get get I don't this is this is
like I said could be totally off but
like then you've then you're putting it
up back up to the finance people it's
like okay listen now there's a 20% risk
of you know whatever cyber incident at
10 million you you run the math you know
like well yeah so so I think you know
it's very complicated and a lot of this
is just completely hypo itical like
speculation but I think a lot of Finance
teams would probably come back and say
you know like well why can't you just
spend less on bug bunny like why can't
you offer lower bounties like and still
we're still incentivizing people to hack
but like why can't you know why can't
you pay 5K crits instead of 20K crits
right like it's still incentivizing and
putting money where our mouth is but
like why do we need to spend you know
20K on a critical when we could pay 20K
for a critical or 5K for a critical yeah
um and you
know that's a that's a difficult one or
like if you go over budget and you need
to pull money from other places and it's
like okay where do we pull like where do
we decide that we don't need money for
so that we can spend it on bug Bounty or
you know like so it's a very complicated
like this why I don't want your job dude
why I do not want your job because I
would get in these meetings I'd be like
listen here like like and finance would
not like me at all no no I don't think
so no yeah so I mean like this is like
the the weird like complicated side of
like the backend side where you know
when you I think you get a little more
respect when you look at programs who
have paid so much money or pay like a
ton of money all the time because when
you think about it from a cash flow
perspective or even just a budgeting
perspective the fact that they're able
to continually get that amount of money
or get like or have those types of funds
to spend on bug Bounty says a lot about
where the company's head is at for
security right like I think all of the
things that you want are totally
reasonable and I would like them too but
it it comes from a very privileged uh
point of view from a security
perspective where it basically assumes
that like all the upper leadership
including the people in Finance and
Accounting value security to like a high
level and think that security is worth
like an act like a dollar value enough
to say like okay yeah we're going to put
like a million dollars a year or
whatever towards paying bounties not
even like the platform fees or anything
else just like bounties right and that
is a line item and so I think you know
it just you have to have that sort of
Buy in from upper leadership and that
kind of stuff and having everybody else
think that it's as important and again I
think this is why things like cyber
insurance for example have started to
make a bit of a change where when a
company has a cyber security per
insurance policy that says that they're
gonna you know if they have a breach
they're going to have to pay pay out
like $10 million or whatever well then
depending on how much you're spending on
bug Bounty that's way worth it because
then you don't have to fall on your
cybercity insurance policy and pay out a
bunch of money and have all these other
problems there is an actual cost like
cost benefit analysis that you can do
there but when when you're like we just
want to pay more in bounties like it's
very hard to justify like if Finance for
example like the situation I said
Finance say oh why can't we just pay 5K
crits instead of 20K crits how do you
generate the data that says well by
paying 5K we're going to get less
submissions we're going to like all like
Quant
we're going to get this many less
submissions and that's going to account
for like this much less money but this
much more risk and that risk equates to
this much potential cyber security risk
and like there's so much like ma like
you might as well like legit be like an
insurance actuator when you're trying to
calculate this kind of stuff and it just
it's so complicated that I think a lot
of programs just take what they can get
and they pay what they can and they hold
on to the money that they can and when
you have programs that have a ton of
budget and a ton of respect for their
security team in their bug Bounty
programs it shows and how they can spend
their bannies
but it it's usually pretty obvious I
don't know yeah I I hope that answers
that that was a hard one to answer it
does and and you need the data you know
that's that that is a good a good a good
point and that takes a lot of work to
get and it's not super readily available
I will say something though when you
mentioned uh
Insurance the the insurance piece is is
really interesting because I bet after a
breach your insurance premiums go
up a lot you know um what happens when
you get in a car accident yeah exactly
fault so you know I bet that 110 Million
number that uh you know a lot of people
saw that number I think for MGM I think
I'm remembering the number right and
we're like whoa that's crazy and then
other people were like oh it's just
covered by cyber insurance I'm like MGM
has a paying bug money program right
yeah yeah and and so um you know cyber
cyber insurance that amount is going to
go go up substantially uh and so I don't
know it's it's crazy I would love to see
the calculations that they're doing like
I would love to know how they're waiting
because I mean this is what actuaries do
right they they do like these really
complicated mathematical um like
probabilities on all these different
things happening I'd love to know what
sort of um factors that they're thinking
about when they're calculating that kind
of cyber cyber security Insurance stuff
because um it would be really
interesting to see how they weighing
like the the risk just like kind of what
I talked about right like okay we lower
our criticals so that we can pay more
bounties or more individual bounties
right in theory but what does that do to
risk does that increase the risk of us
getting a worse vulnerability that we
didn't know about not through the bug
Bounty program or does it increase the
number of bugs that we're going to
receive because now we can pay more or
like you I don't know you're kind of
paying the price anyway yeah yeah yeah
right like I don't know it's that one
more Point here before we move along
okay because we're already an hour and I
I can't spend super long today
um this was going to the Staffing versus
bug Bounty
money
conversation bug Bounty bug Bounty
doesn't take a break you know bug Bounty
doesn't spend time on a useless email
you know bug Bounty doesn't do any of
that crap you know um
and I think that should make it a much
easier conversation with with Finance
it's like listen when we hire someone we
are agreeing to pay them x amount of
money regardless of their performance
regardless of their their uh you know
whatever right that's inherently risky
because you don't know how they're going
to perform and you do your best to to
pick somebody who will but it's a risk
and you don't have that risk with B
because you're only ever paying for
results and I think that should make the
sell much easier like listen listen
Finance every single time we pay out
here
it's it's actually fixing something and
you're buying something you know like it
you're getting some result um so I don't
know that's just my feel fre to and then
we'll move along it's just crazy
complicated calculus right it's like
yeah that that is that is true you know
until you pay enough crits and then
suddenly the math is all out of whack so
yeah it's it's just one of those weird
things that like I think from a bug
bunny Hunter's perspective it doesn't
matter so much the nitty-gritty but you
can you can
tell sort of like how Finance is when
you're dealing with a lot of programs
based on like how fast they pay and how
much they pay and how loose they are
with bounties and all that kind of stuff
yeah all right dude um we're an hour in
I'm looking at the rest of the topics
and they are not at all related
to okay actually I've got one one semi-
related one and then we'll cut it and
we'll move the content to next week um
it keep it sort of on topic with this
whole um hacker versus program thing let
me ask you this um what
is what is your thought
on Walling off
endpoints as a permanent fix and as a
Band-Aid fix and do does it happen and
like like with a wa or like with a with
a reverse proxy um yeah what are your
thoughts oh it happens all the time for
sure I I think the greatest example of
this is like you know like a year ago or
six months ago and all those zero days
kept popping up and like Apache and
spring Boot and there were all these
really core fundamental problems um the
first line of fixes that you would see
would be add this to your detection
rules add this you know block requests
that are containing these parameters and
stuff right so that for sure happens and
I think it's a great immediate fix
because when you have something that
affects you number one priority is
making sure that you're not vulnerable
and the only way to do that is to either
patch the code and deploy it or to stop
requests and then patch the code and
deploy it and so I think a lot of
companies first thing they want to do is
lock that down make sure that they you
know they can't be be exploited
externally then they can figure out you
know what they need to change what they
need to fix whatever as long as it's not
going to impact things and then they can
go from there um I don't really see any
problems with it I I definitely think
from like a security response
perspective it's probably like the best
and fastest thing that you can do in the
moment often times if it's just a normal
bug Bounty report depending on the
severity I don't know about if it needs
to be handled in that sense um maybe
okay yeah then yeah probably like
I think I would want the program to
respond as soon as possible maybe you
can explain a little bit more of the
cont let me ask this because I think
we've had a a debate I think this is
actually in the last hacker program
debate where where we were like okay you
know vul in a third party just wa it off
and you're like just wa it off like you
know what do you mean just WAFF it off
like that takes time and effort and I'm
like just wa it off man it's just an
engine X config or like a you know going
into Cloud flare whatever but maybe I'm
I'm wrong about that you know like and I
don't know if this is actually something
that you're doing in your day-to-day
whether you've got like teams Associated
for this but let's say you want to wa
off an endpoint or like you know engine
X reverse proxy off an endpoint um
like does this go through the the
whole this is such a weird question does
this go through the whole Dev process or
you like just like this is this is now I
feel embarrassed you know asking this
way you just SSH into prod and like
modif thing like I would say at most
companies that have at least 50
employees that's never going to happen
um smaller smaller startups like one
thing you'll notice startups less
employees less process less procedure
everything's a lot more Scrappy
everything is much more like oh just
tell Dan the SSH into the box and like
you know whatever like yeah exactly like
and prod exactly right like that type of
stuff once you start to grow and there's
a lot more procedures and processes in
place you have like you know people in
charge and managing and stuff you the
those things are harder for a lot of
different reasons at a fundamental level
it's a security reason right that people
shouldn't just be able to like into the
box and change that kind of stuff right
like that's that's risky um so typically
there's what I think is commonly
referred to as like a break glass
process where essentially in these p0o
scenarios there are certain layers of
approval whether that's through like it
or director or some highlevel manager
who's m in charge of this process they
might get paged on call or something
like that um you know the people who are
basically in in charge of these
emergency response processes and there
will be special approvals that can go in
place to push a change like that um and
and usually it's not just that like one
person has the ability to do that it
does need to go through some layers but
those layers exist for those for those
pzero those super high critical risk
cases where something needs to happen at
two o'clock in the morning or whatever
wow yeah that's it's it's so much I I
think that's something that's really
high value to understand too because I
think um there are there have been some
scenarios in the past where you I was
just reading through some old reports
where you can
access where you can bypass those sort
of engine X config stuff it was on the
on the um you know
um 2023 top web hacking techniques one
one of the top ones was like here here's
these characters you stick at the ends
of URLs or whatever and you can you know
you can get through and I just love I
love the idea of that and um and so I
think it it really makes a lot of sense
for researchers to pay attention to
security architecture in that way and if
people are waing off endpoints and and
uh you know doing Apache blocks or
whatever then knowing what kind of
backend stack is in place and how the
frontend
um proxy is dealing with various routes
and and what data will be stripped out
of those URLs um that that that's really
huge and I think something that a lot of
people a lot of bug Hunters could
benefit from and I also think it's
something that a lot of Bug Hunter bug
Hunters like me rather than Enterprise
uh absec people that have a better
understanding of of how these
architectures flow um I think people
like me overlook this a lot because we
don't understand you know okay this is
what the whole flow looks like and this
is what people do in an incident
response situation they WAFF it off so I
don't know it's interesting yeah it's
it's definitely very interesting and I
think that architecture side is really
valuable like that's one of the big
things that I've learned from like the
company sort of like you know
engineering side is every company is
very different with how they structure
things but a lot of it can be very
similar especially just like the core
like aspects of how it's working right
like there's some Edge proxy that's
going to the load balancer that's going
to individual instances of code that is
a service right or whatever like and
like that's running some deployment of
the thing that an engineer wrote that's
a very common structure like you have
Services service based architecture and
then you have these routing and the
routing happens one of a handful of ways
whether it's through like internal
engine X or kubernetes pods or Docker
clusters or whatever like you know they
they have some way of communicating
between services and from the front end
to the back end and then there's some
you know High performant layer that's
handling the request cuz large companies
I don't think people realize like the
scale of requests that they're dealing
with right like large Fortune 500
companies are dealing with hundreds of
millions of requests uh per hour per
minute right like it's it's like lots
right if you think about how many for
instance Facebook has a two billion
active daily users or something right
like just think about how many requests
like two billion people are generated
every single you know page load triggers
jav files like 20 requests on a good day
you know it's like
right so like from an engineering
architecture perspective there's like
this is a huge huge like problem to try
and even solve in the first place and
somehow they have this Solution that's
been architected to like deal with this
massive load of requests and figuring
out how that works and like how that's
doing that and what path your request is
taking can tell you a lot about the
possibilities that you have for lateral
movement and different ways to attack it
and like what kinds of characters will
and won't pass and um you know where am
I getting stopped at the edge layer or
like some middle layer or am I getting
stopped at the back end like where where
does this all sort of how does this
together you know authorization at this
middle level is there some way around
that you know that data dude that would
be so interesting to me and I really
wish company and maybe there's not like
these little diagrams in your
organization or whatever but I imagine
there would be for onboarding um if I
got access to those man that would be so
awesome you know to to see like okay
this application that I'm working on you
know and if it was like actually
detailed too cuz like you'll often see
like
all right here's a little cylinder thing
and this is the database like three
boxes and it's like external request
front end back end okay great thanks you
know but like if he was actually
detailed like
okay coming in through this you know
engine X this reverse boxing with a
proxy pass you know and it's hitting
this and that if it was actually really
detailed like that that would be so
helpful and so fascinating and what ends
up happening is is when we get at these
ssrf we have to to figure it out you
know and it just H it'd be really cool
to actually see it one thing I will say
is probably a good place to look for
that is engineering blogs okay yeah
because a lot of these companies have
engineering blogs that um I hate to
break it to literally nobody reads this
I'm really sorry if somebody listening
is like an engineer who spent like three
months writing this really in-depth
engineering blog post for their company
this is what I'm talking about pay the
freaking bounties instead of you know
like hiring people to write blog posts
like I'm just saying like I see this a
lot where like these companies like put
this huge in-depth like engineering blog
post together and I'm like who is this
for like this is actually for nobody but
some like okr right this is nobody's
actually reading it maybe like you know
a handful of people read it and the
people think it's cool think it's really
cool but like almost nobody actually
sees it however from a bug money
perspective it's really really
interesting to hear Engineers talk about
their own internal infrastructure and
how stuff works and how Stuff
communicates and the problem spaces
they're encountering and like usually
they're very happy to talk about those
things in these engineering blogs so if
the company has an engineering blog I
would probably go read it there's got to
be there's got to be a diagram somewhere
that's what I'm talking about man like
it what kind of big company is going to
win Top Talent when they say hey um
we're we're not allowing you to go write
a blog right like on company time right
like like you know if the if the person
really wanted to do that no they would
look like [__] and no one would go
work for them right well and from the
company's perspective this is promoting
the security brand and like bragging
about the capabilities internally and
attracting talent and all that kind of
stuff so there is a justification it
does nothing for for but but listen
nobody reads it right you know maybe
your internal people read it and that's
cool and that's great with onboarding if
it adds value there then then there's
that right for all I know I'm an anomaly
and I'm the one who's not reading it but
everybody else does everyone besides you
reads you know these engineering blogs
um but but you know bug Bounty doesn't
doesn't spend three months writing a
blog post you know like you just it's
such a clear exchange for money and
you're you're rolling the dice in so
many different ways why don't you grab
onto the one thing that's for certain
you
know this is my thought all
right any anything else there we want to
do you want do you want to rebuttal that
or should we close it there no no I mean
I listen by B is a really easy way to be
like hey we just spent this much money
on a vulnerability um balancing that
with the rest of like the Finance BS is
really difficult but I think it's not as
difficult as a lot of a lot of companies
do and the ones who running vdps because
God knows why like if you're making more
than $5 million a year in Revenue you
should have a bug Bounty program that
pays money yeah even if it's a small
Bounty yeah yeah I agree man yeah all
right let's wrap it there all right
peace that's spot
see and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
list listening and if you want more
critical thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there
[Music]